<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[@octopress]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.eamca.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.eamca.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-01T14:43:31+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.eamca.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[spondbob]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[spondbob@eamca.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Networking]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/raspberry-pi-networking/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-13T17:05:47+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/raspberry-pi-networking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to have troubles to set my Raspberry Pi to get connected to the existing network because I do not have keyboard and monitor to directly access it. The only thing I can do is plug off the sdcard and insert it into my laptop to get access to the OS.</p>

<p>But, my laptop is running on Windows, it does not recognize EXT partition. So, I can not easily modify the network configuration of the system. However, there is one partition on the sdcard that based on FAT32 which is can be easily read and write by Windows. This partition is boot partition. Now, I will show you how I can easily set up my network connection, whether to connect to LAN cable, existing WiFi, or even set my own access point!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Before we begin, you might need to check my <a href="http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/bikinibottom/">Raspberry Pi&rsquo;s specification</a> beforehand.</p>

<p>The idea is a service will read a configuration file located in FAT32 partition during boot time. This will allow us to easily modify the configuration file before the Raspberry Pi is booted. Basically there 3 are steps to set this up.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Create service</p>

<p>This is my simple service script located at <code>/etc/systemd/system/</code>. While booting, this service will execute a &ldquo;reader&rdquo; script.
<script src="http://gist-it.eamca.com/github/spondbob/bikinibottom-mode/raw/master/bikinibottom-mode.service"></script></p></li>
<li><p>Create the reader</p>

<p>This reader file is to decide which network configuration going to be used. The reader reads a textfile which called MODE.txt file. Basically, MODE file contains the filename of the configuration files which will be executed by this reader.
<script src="http://gist-it.eamca.com/github/spondbob/bikinibottom-mode/raw/master/bikinibottom-mode.sh"></script>
Put it in a <code>your_filename.service</code> then enable it by <code>#systemctl enable your_filename</code>. And here is a minimal MODE file as a switch.
<script src="http://gist-it.eamca.com/github/spondbob/bikinibottom-mode/raw/master/MODE.txt"></script></p></li>
<li><p>Last but not least, the configurations</p>

<p>Basically you can put anything what you like here, as long as the file name is included in MODE.txt to be executed when booting. Here I provide some of my network configuration.</p>

<p>Static IP for LAN interface enables direct access to the pi.
<script src="http://gist-it.eamca.com/github/spondbob/bikinibottom-mode/raw/master/scripts/eth0.sh"></script></p>

<p>Wireless configuration to connect to existing WiFi. Use <code>wpa_passphrase your_SSID your_password</code> to setup the profile.
<script src="http://gist-it.eamca.com/github/spondbob/bikinibottom-mode/raw/master/scripts/wlan0.sh"></script></p>

<p>Setup access point with <a href="https://github.com/oblique/create_ap">ap_create</a>
<script src="http://gist-it.eamca.com/github/spondbob/bikinibottom-mode/raw/master/scripts/ap.sh"></script></p></li>
</ol>


<p>You might take a look <a href="https://github.com/spondbob/bikinibottom-mode/">the complete project</a> on my Github. Feel free to drop a message if you got any questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[bikinibottom]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/bikinibottom/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-05T17:30:57+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/bikinibottom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This page is specifically introduced my Raspberry Pi, bikinibottom, with its functionalities and features. Since at the time this page is written, bikinibottom is a Raspberry Pi runs Arch Linux ARM. Its mainly usage is as a standalone development server.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The attached hardware is listed as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>Raspberry Pi Model B</li>
<li>SanDisk Ultra SDHC Card 16GB</li>
<li>Nano USB WiFi EDIMAX EW-7811Un</li>
<li>Power adaptor 750mA, 1A, and 2A</li>
</ul>


<p>The most usage applications are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Web servers: apache2, nginx</li>
<li>Database servers: postgre, MongoDB</li>
<li>Programming languages: PHP, python, ruby (on Rails)</li>
<li>Multimedia: omxplayer, mopidy</li>
<li>Torrent: rutorrent</li>
<li>Other: rvm, git, tmuxinator</li>
</ul>


<p>Partition table:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>Disk /dev/mmcblk0: 14.9 GiB, 15931539456 bytes, 31116288 sectors
</span><span class='line'>Units: sectors of 1 * 512 = 512 bytes
</span><span class='line'>Sector size (logical/physical): 512 bytes / 512 bytes
</span><span class='line'>I/O size (minimum/optimal): 512 bytes / 512 bytes
</span><span class='line'>Disklabel type: dos
</span><span class='line'>Disk identifier: 0x417ee54b
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Device         Boot  Start      End  Sectors  Size Id Type
</span><span class='line'>/dev/mmcblk0p1        2048   186367   184320   90M  c W95 FAT32 (LBA)
</span><span class='line'>/dev/mmcblk0p2      186368 31116287 30929920 14.8G  5 Extended
</span><span class='line'>/dev/mmcblk0p5      188416 31116287 30927872 14.8G 83 Linux</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Merdeka!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/merdeka/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-24T20:03:57+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/merdeka</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was 69 years ago. August 17, 1945 was the independence day of Indonesia. I&rsquo;m not going to say anything what has been done during that time, but here it is Republic of Indonesia in 2014.</p>

<p>The good news is, this year we are going to have new president! Believes and hopes are on his shoulders. Time to roll up our sleeves folks.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s get back to this 4-years away series. I feel a shame as I didn&rsquo;t join the ceremony this morning. I have been prepared for this day night before. Alarm clock, time to catch the tram, the stop, and last but not least weather was checked. Everything seems perfect except: Get up early on Sunday morning. I missed my chance to unlock the achievement &ldquo;Attend independence day ceremony for 2 timess in a row during 20s&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to say congratulations to people who managed to celebrate this day like one of them at Federation Square, and every single person who has brought us to this 69.</p>

<p>Merdeka!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ancora Imparo]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/ancora-imparo/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-28T23:55:05+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/ancora-imparo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good Morning.]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/good-morning/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-05T09:20:44+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.eamca.com/blog/2014/good-morning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, let&rsquo;s begin with a warm message.</p>

<p>Howdy you there! yeah you, it&rsquo;s you!<br />
Nah, nobody care.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been a long time since I got this idea to set up a new blog in English. And here it is, this <a href="http://octopress.org/">happy typing octopus</a> squized me up. Look how happy he is. Took 2 days for me to get rid of the tentacles and this octopus keeps smile on me. Be a good boy.</p>

<p>Anyway, this writing is not only to show off my beautiful hand writing, I know, but under some circumstances is easier to explain it like this. Just let me write what I want and this time is in English, take it.</p>

<p>As I mention before, while am writing in English you have to do the same. There will be a lot of people coming here, so make sure you are already prepared to be known. Yeaah.</p>

<p>One more thing, let me say this one. I know it&rsquo;s silly, you have your own dreams to do anything (as please as to this octopus) and there your ego come. Make sure where your foot is going to step on and towards which way. Yes, to the right one.</p>

<p>Good Morning, sunshine.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
